I hate it when I'm right.
嫌な予感 当たっちゃった…
ん～？
虹夏たちが
作っていったんだよ
Nijika and her friends made them.
But the typhoon still came in the end.
結局 台風 来ちゃいましたね
Well, it's not like rain charms
actually affect the weather.
まあ てるてる坊主で
どうにかなるわけじゃないからさ
Even the people who bought tickets
might not come at this rate.
この様子じゃ
チケット買った人すら
来ないんじゃないですか？
みんな 客の入り見て
心折れなきゃいいですけど…
I hope they're not too
heartbroken by the small crowd.
練習 頑張ったのに
かわいそうですね
They practiced so hard for this.
I feel bad for them.
バンド続けてくなら
Real bands get screwed over
by life all the time.
こんな理不尽
たくさんあるんだから
They need to learn to make it
through any situation.
どんな状況でも
乗り越えられるようにならないと
ハンカチありますよ
I've got a handkerchief.
あっち行ってよ
Oh, go away.
Tickets go on sale at 5 pm
Looks like my friends can't come either.
友達も
やっぱり来られないみたいです
S-Same with my parents.
う… うちの親も
M-My grandma was supposed
to look after Futari,
そ… 祖母が ふたりを
見ててくれるはずだったんですけど
b-but now she can't come, so...
こ… 来られなくなっちゃって
Yeah. Makes sense...
そっか… だよね
Our audience is going to be
less than half of what we expected.
半分以下に
なっちゃいましたね お客さん
しょうがないよ　切り替えていこ！
Well, it is what it is!
Let's take it in stride!
Yes, of course!
Nijika-chan always stays so cheerful,
no matter what happens.
虹夏ちゃんは
どんなときも明るいな
うわっ
ちょっと～ もう 緊張感ないなあ
C'mon, look alive there!
It's the low-pressure system. So sleepy...
低気圧…
That's right. Even during the concert
where I was just helping...
そういえば
助っ人で入ったライブのときも
She worked so hard to cheer me up
when I was scared.
怖がってた私を
元気づけてくれたっけ
O-Okay!
よ… よし！　私も…
For today's concert...
今日のライブ 盛り上げていくぞ！
Sergeant for a Day
I'm gonna bring the hype!
ぼっちちゃん
Bocchi-chan, this is a serious concert.
今日は真面目なライブだから
ふざけちゃダメだよ
No messing around.
You really like that outfit, huh?
それ 気に入ってるんですね
Y-Yes...
あっ はい…
フッ
ひゃあ～ すごい雨！
Wow, look at that rain!
ぼっちちゃん 来たよ～
Bocchi-chan, I'm here!
あっ おねえさん
M-Ma'am!
えっ お前
ぼっちちゃん目当てで来たの？
Oh, you came here for Bocchi-chan?
Heck yeah! Yay!
そうだよ イエーイ
Y-You know each other?
えっ お知り合いなんですか？
あたしの大学のときの後輩
She was my junior in college.
ねえねえ
うっ
Betcher havin' an afterparty tonight, right?
今日のライブ
打ち上げするんだよね？
Picked an izakaya yet?
居酒屋 もう決めたの～？
You reek of booze!
酒くさっ
I know a good one, 'kay? 'Kay?
おいしい場所 知ってますよ
ねえ ねえ～
How did you become even more
of a pain in the ass?
また 一段と
めんどくさいヤツになったな
She's as annoying as a college student
who just learned about drinking parties.
飲み会 覚えたての大学生に通ずる
ウザさがありますね
And look at you! You're soaked!
ってか お前
ビチョビチョじゃねえか！
あっ
I'm so wet!
ぬれた～
あっ ひとりちゃん！
Hitori-chan!
あっ
The girls from our street concert!
前の路上ライブのときの！
えっ き… 来てくれたんですか？
Y-You really came?
もちろん！
Of course we did!
We're your fans!
だって私たち
ひとりちゃんのファンだし
We'll be expecting a performance
powerful enough to blow away the typhoon!
台風 吹っ飛ばすくらい
かっこいい演奏 期待してますね
ハッ
ウヘッ ヘヘヘ ファン…
Fans...
ウヘヘヘ フフッ…
Y-You are Hitori-chan, right?
ひ… ひとりちゃんだよね？
Did we have the wrong person?
人違いかも…
私のファン！
My fans!
Congrats! Congrats! Congrats!
おめでとう
おめでとう おめでと～！
My fans!
私のファン～！
クッ グフフフフ…
人違いでした～！
It is the wrong person!
ウヒッ ウヒヒヒ グフフ…
雨 これから
どんどん強くなってくみたいです
Looks like the rain's
only going to get worse.
Worse than this?
今よりも？
Yes...
はい
Maybe we should just stream it
as a no-audience concert
ここは ライブの様子を配信して
始めから無観客ライブだった
ということに…
and act like it was supposed
to be that way from the start.
しない しない！
We're not doing that!
そんなの 今から誰も見ないし
It's way too late to get anyone to tune in,
何人かは
もう来てくれてるんだから
and we've already got a couple people here...
だだだだ… 大丈夫です！
I-I-I-It'll be okay!
ん？
わっ 私たちの え… 演奏を
A-As long as we have p-people
waiting to see us p-perform!
Ripe Mangos
ま… 待っててくれる人が
いるんだから！
Don't you dare!
それ 絶対やめて！
ちょっと進化してるし
She's evolved somehow...
Ripe Mangos
もう 本番直前ですけど
やっぱり お客さん少ないですね
It's just about start time, and there's
really not many people out there...
でも ほかのバンドの
ファンの人もいるし
But the other bands' fans are here too,
みんな 聴いてくれるよ
and I'm sure they'll all listen to us!
なんだかんだで
And I'm sure more will arrive if we start.
始まったら
どんどん増えてくるはず
ねえ…
あっ
Hey, you ever heard of this
first group? Kessoku Band?
１番目の
結束バンドって知ってる？
Don't know. Don't care.
知らない 興味な～い
Yeah, seems like a waste of time.
見とくのタルいね
W-Well, we're new,
so of course no one knows us!
アッハハ
結成したばっかで
まだ知られてないからね
Don't let it get you down!
落ち込まないで！
E-Exactly!
そ… そうですよね
Don't sweat it. Don't sweat it.
気にしない 気にしない
R-Right!
は… はい
O-Okay, it's almost time!
よっ… よ～し そろそろ出番だね
Let's do that concert, you guys!
みんな ライブ頑張るぞ～！
お～っ！
お… お～
ハア…
はじめまして 結束バンドです
A pleasure to meet you!
We're Kessoku Band!
本日は お足元の悪い中
お越しいただき
We appreciate your kind attendance
in spite of this awful weather!
誠に ありがとうございます
アッハハ
Kita-chan, that's way too polite
for a rock band!
喜多ちゃん ロックバンドなのに
礼儀正しすぎ～
アハハハ…
I want my mango box!
完熟マンゴー かぶりたい！
っていうか 今すぐ
この場から消え去りたい～！
Actually, I want to disappear altogether!
Well, let's get to that first song!
じゃあ 早速 １曲目 いきます
Please lend your ears to our original song:
聴いてください
私たちのオリジナル曲で
"Guitar, Solitude, and the Blue Planet"!
“ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星”
A sudden evening shower falls
♪ 突然降る夕立
あぁ傘もないや嫌
And yeah, it figures,
I don't have an umbrella...
♪ 空のご機嫌なんか知らない
Who cares how the sky's feeling, anyway?
♪ 季節の変わり目の服は…
When it's time for the seasons to change
What are you supposed to wear? Who knows?
Nijika-chan's drumming feels a little slow.
なんか 虹夏ちゃん
さっきからドラム もたついてるな
Spring and fall... yeah, where'd they go?
The pressure of information, suffocating
And Kita-san's making mistakes
she didn't make in practice.
喜多さんもリハで できてたのに
ずっとミスってるし
A spiral of vertigo
Ryo-san and Nijika-chan
aren't in sync at all.
リョウさんも虹夏ちゃんと
息が合ってない
Don't know where I am
♪ わたしはどこにいる
I can hear myself breathing
so loud, so loud...
♪ こんなに　こんなに
息の音がするのに
But why? I can't hear the
sounds of the world...
♪ 変だね　世界の音がしない
It's not enough, not enough,
No one knows I'm here
♪ 足りない　足りない
誰にも気づかれない
I screamed when I couldn't
make a scribble of a sound
♪ 殴り書きみたいな音
出せない状態で…
We're not playing the way we usually do...
みんな いつもと全然違う
Who am I supposed to show "just who I am" to?
♪ 「ありのまま」なんて
誰に見せるんだ
♪ 馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
So I'm singing just like the fool I am
♪ ぶちまけちゃおうか　星に
Let's lay it all out to the stars!
That was "Guitar, Solitude,
and the Blue Planet"!
“ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星”でした
Yeah, what a waste of time.
やっぱ 全然パッとしないわ
早く来るんじゃなかったね
We should've showed up later.
Um...
あっ えっと…
喜多ちゃん 次の曲紹介しないと！
Kita-chan, you need to
introduce the next song!
R-Right!
はっ はい！
The next is another of our original songs,
次も私たちのオリジナル曲で
つい先日…
and it's one we just wrote...
Our performance and
our songs still aren't good enough.
私たち 演奏も曲も まだまだだ
けど…
But...
えっ？
フッ
I refuse to let it stay this way!
このままじゃ嫌だ！
That band's songs sound to me
♪ あのバンドの歌がわたしには
like shrill laughter all around
♪ 甲高く響く笑い声に聞こえる
♪ あのバンドの歌がわたしには
That band's songs are to me
♪ つんざく踏切の音みたい
like the piercing clang of a railway crossing
♪ 背中を押すなよ
Don't push me forward
♪ もうそこに列車が来る
There's a train coming
I close my eyes
♪ 目を閉じる　暗闇に差す後光
There's a halo in the darkness
I cover my ears
♪ 耳塞ぐ　確かに刻む鼓動
There's a steady beating pulse within
♪ 胸の奥　身を揺らす心臓
Deep in my chest
My heart makes my body sway
♪ ほかに何も聴きたくない
I don't want to hear anything else
Nothing but the sounds I'm making
♪ わたしが放つ音以外
アハッ！
あっ…
Hey, not bad!
ちょっと いいじゃん
ねっ！
Yeah!
めっちゃ かっこよかった！
That was super cool!
ねえ～！
Yeah!
フフ～ン
見事なドヤ顔
Magnificent smugface.
ヘヘッ
ん？
あっ あっ ああ…
フフッ
That was our second song, "That Band"!
２曲目“あのバンド”でした
Now, here's our last song!
じゃあ次 ラストの曲です！
Kaomise
Cheers!
Well done, all!
かんぱ～い！
お疲れさまです
Nice work on the concert.
ライブ よく頑張った
今日は私の おごりだから飲め
This is all on my tab, so drink up.
お姉ちゃん ありがと～
あたしたち飲めないけど
Thanks, Sis! Though we don't drink...
先輩 好き～！
ううっ
Love ya, Senpai!
お前は自腹だよ くっつくな！
You pay your own way. Get off.
っていうか この方 誰ですか？
Who exactly is this woman, if I may ask?
Genius bassist and unparalleled
bass-lover, Kikuri Hiroi!
誰よりもベースを愛する
天才ベーシスト
廣井きくりで～す
ベースは昨日 飲み屋に忘れました
I left my bass at a drinking party yesterday,
but I forgot which drinking party, so...
どこの飲み屋かも分かんない
エヘヘ…
一瞬で矛盾したんですけど…
Instant self-contradiction.
私 よくライブ行ってました
I've been to a lot of your concerts.
Aw, for real? You got good taste, hon!
えっ ホント？　君 見る目あるね！
観客に酒吹きかけたり
You spray booze on the audience.
ブ～ッ！
泥酔しながらのライブ 最高です！
Blind drunk concerts are the best!
アハハハ ごめん 歌詞 飛んだ
Sorry, forgot the words!
まあ でも ライブって
But hey, that's how concerts go sometimes!
そういうもんじゃん？
怒んなよ うっせえな～！
Don't be mad, you jerks!
顔面 踏んでもらったのも
I treasure my memory of
you stepping on my face.
良い思い出です
Thank you, Shinjuku!
新宿 ありがと～！
I love you mother******s!
カスども最高！
マザー×××××！
私ってロックのこと まだ
ぜ～んぜん理解してないみたいです
There's so much about rock
I have yet to learn.
It might be okay not to learn all that.
多分 理解しなくても大丈夫かも
Glad your concert turned out well in the end!
ライブ 最後は
大盛り上がりで よかったね
観客10人くらいでしたけど
For an audience of ten, sure.
でも その人たちは全員
満足してくれたじゃん
But every single one of 'em left happy!
ですかね
Yeah, guess so!
まっ 続けてれば
どんどんファン増えてくよ
Well, keep it up, and you'll pick up fans.
Work hard for your next concert.
次のライブでも頑張れよ
ちゃんとノルマ代は払ってな
And make sure you pay your quota fee.
最後のセリフさえなければ
感動したのに
That'd be really inspiring
without the last bit...
You worked really hard today too,
Bocchi-chan...
ぼっちちゃんも
今日は すごい頑張った
って… えっ！
真っ白に燃え尽きてる？
Wait, why's she a husk?!
ぼっちちゃん 灰にならないで！
Bocchi-chan, don't turn to ash!
僕は もう疲れたよ…
I've grown so tired...
おめでとう　おめでとう
Congrats! Congrats!
それ 違うやつ！
That's the wrong show!
Go on, order as much food as you like!
ほら 料理 好きなの頼んで
あっ は… はい
R-Right...
Watcha gettin', Bocchi-chan?
ぼっちちゃん 何にする？
I was thinking of ordering karaage!
あたしはね
から揚げ頼みたいかな～
S-Sounds good...
あっ い… いいですね
What are you doing?
But this looks pretty good too!
ねえ それって…
ん？
Isstagramming!
イソスタです　私 大臣なので
I'm the minister!
Minister?
大臣？
それってさ 何が楽しいの？
What do you like so much about that, anyway?
What?
えっ？
I guess it's like
giving people a piece of the fun...
楽しい気持ちの
お裾分けっていうか
Isn't everything more fun when
you share it with your friends?
友達が楽しそうだと
楽しくないですか？
Kit-aura
Kit-aura!
うっ
キタ～ン
Kit-aura
Nice!
いいぞ！　喜多ちゃんパワーで
Use that Kita-chan power of yours
to purge my sister's twisted spirit!
お姉ちゃんの ひねくれ体質を
浄化しちゃえ
ひねくれ？
店長さん 優しいじゃないですか
Twisted?
But the manager's really nice!
Kit-aura
Kit-aura! Kit-aura!
キタキタ～ン
やめろ 死ぬ…
Stop it.
You're killing me.
I-I've made up my mind. Here's the menu.
あっ あの…
決まったので メニューどうぞ
Thanks!
ありがとう！
Let's see...
え～っと じゃあ私
I'll have the avocado and
cream cheese pinchos!
アボカドとクリームチーズの
ピンチョス
うっ
And the Spanish omelette
with hollandaise sauce!
あと…
スパニッシュオムレツの
オランデーズソース添え下さい
なんて？
The what?
Here! The omelette with hollandaise.
このオムレツ
オランデーズソースのやつです
オランダ？
Hollanda-what?
Kita-san's so fluent in trendy gibberish.
喜多さん
Nice! Nice!
また意味不明な
おしゃれそうなことを言っている
Keep ordering!
I bet she can casually
walk into a Starpucks.
喜多さんって スタパとか
普通に入れちゃうんだろうな
む… 難しい注文とかも
サラッとしちゃって…
I bet she could make the most complicated
orders like it was nothing.
ペペロプリプリパピプペポ
ペロぺパチーナのショートで
I'll have a short puri-puri pepero
papipupepo peroppe pacina!
キタ～ン
Kit-aura!
ぼっちちゃんは？　何頼む？
Bocchi-chan? What do you want?
ハッ
Oh...
I w-won't be the way I usually am!
きょ… 今日の私は違うんだ
私も何か おしゃれなチョイスを！
I'll make a trendy choice too!
Bocchi-chan?
ぼっちちゃん？
Th-Then, I'll have the M-Machu Picchu Ruins,
あっ じゃあ マッ…
マチュピチュ遺跡のミシシッピ川
Mississippi River,
Grand Canyon San Diego hash...
グランドキャニオン
サンディエゴ盛り合わせで
ふむふむ
マチュピチュ マチュピチュ…
M-Machu Picchu, Machu Picchu, Machu Picchu...
って あん？　どこだ？
Where's that exactly?
ん？　ん？
Oh, I read it wrong...
あっ 間違えました
フライドポテトです
I meant fries.
どんな読み間違えだよ
アハハ…
How did you read that wrong?
Pickled fish offals for me.
私は酒盗
How old're you again?
君 いくつ？
You're already moving on?
お前 もう次いってんのかよ
Izakayas are like my home ground, y'know?
居酒屋っていったら
私のホームグラウンドじゃ
ないですか～
Hey, how do you read this one?
なんでしょう？
私も読めないです
It's my first time at an izakaya,
Which one? I don't think
I can read it either...
初めて来たけど
居酒屋って少し楽しいかも
but they're actually kind of fun...
You're so knowledgeable, Ryo-senpai!
リョウ先輩 物知り～！
大人になって
お酒飲めるようになったら
I wonder if they'll be even more fun
when I grow up and can drink.
もっと楽しいのかな
My wife's taste in clothing
changed all of a sudden.
最近 嫁の服の趣味が
突然変わってさ…
ん？
And she suddenly started
locking her smartphone.
スマホも急にロックかけだして
何？　嫁のスマホ見てんの？
What, you check your wife's phone?
No, I just happened to notice.
違えよ　たまたま気付いて
Sounds like cheating to me.
まあ 絶対 浮気だな それ
Yeah, gotta be...
だよな…
But maybe I deserve it.
でも されて当然なのかもな
I'm so busy with work every day...
毎日毎日 仕事 仕事で
You don't deserve it.
当然ってことはないだろ
サビ残続きで
休みの日も接待ゴルフ
Hours of unpaid overtime, forced to spend
my days off golfing with clients...
And when I do get an early break,
I have such a hard time facing her
たまに早く終わっても
家に帰りづらくて
こうやって お前と飲んで…
I go drinking with you instead...
What am I even doing all this work for?
俺 なんのために働いてんだろ
大丈夫かよ おい
Hey, you all right, man?
たまに 駅のホーム見てると
Sometimes I look at the station platform, and
I find myself about to jump onto the tracks.
飛び込みそうになってる自分が
いるんだよな
まあ 飲め飲め
C'mon, have some more to drink.
すんませ～ん　ナカください！
Excuse me! More shochu!
はいよ！　ナカ１丁！
Sure thing! One shochu!
Is life just an unrelenting hell?
人生とは どこまでも地獄なのか
If I can't make my stage
debut in high school,
高校在学中に
デビューできなかったら
私も 一旦は
就職しなきゃいけないんだよね
I'm going to have to get a proper career too.
I'm not smart enough to get into college,
Fail to make debut,
get a job
Graduate high school
Move on to college
大学行けるほど
頭良くないし
私の場合
and I don't even know what I'd go for...
なんのために行くのかも
分からないし…
Sales Results for December
Target: 100
Gotoh            Ozaki            Hasegawa         Koizumi           Ogawa
5th              4th                  3rd                2nd                 1st
え～ 今月の
ところてんの営業売り上げは
Your sales for this month were the
lowest on the team, Gotoh-san.
後藤さんが最下位でした
Gotoh-san again?
また後藤さん？
It's partly the boss being cruel.
部長も意地悪よね
後藤さん辞めさせたいからって
わざと営業部に異動させて
He transferred her to sales
to try to make her quit!
Tokoroten
E-Excuse me...
あっ あっ あの…
と… ところてん買ってください
W-Would you like to buy some tokoroten?
It's well-aged, and it goes down smooth...
年代物で喉越しなめらか…
間に合ってるんで！
No, thank you!
Transferred to
sales department
Fail at door-
to-door sales
Stress quit and
become a shut-in
I see as plain as day
where my Game of Life is going!
手に取るように分かる！
負の人生ゲーム！
Hitori-chan, won't you open up? Please?
ひとりちゃん？
このドアを開けて ね？
You don't have to go back to work.
もう お仕事なんか
しなくていいから
Just come eat dinner with me again!
また お母さんと一緒に
ご飯食べよ ね？
Please?
プハ～
ひいいああ～！
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
ぼっちちゃん
またいつもの発作か？
Another of Bocchi-chan's episodes?
Oh, so that is typical for her!
へえ～　やっぱり これ
いつものことなんだ
If I can't make money with my guitar,
I'll end up a NEET.
早くギターで
食べられるようにならないと…
Her face is scary when it gets like that.
怖いんだよな
ぼっちちゃんの この顔
If I can't make money with my guitar...
Really? I think it's got personality.
そうですか？
結構 味があると思いますけど
マジかよ？
うんうん
Are you for real?
Sandpaper, please.
紙やすり ちょうだい
毎回 この作業 大変ですよね
It's kind of a chore, huh?
ヤバッ ミスったかも
Whoops. Think I botched it.
大丈夫ですよ
ここをこうして… ほら
It's okay.
Just do it like this. See?
They're used to it!
手慣れてんな
Up we go.
よいしょ
面長すぎない？
Did I make her face too long?
えっ？　大体こんな感じですよ
I think it's about right.
Oh, thank you!
あっ ありがとうございます
A-Actually, can I fix it up a little?
や… やっぱり
もう少し修正していいですか？
By the way, Ikuyo.
そういえば 郁代
ぐあっ！
You played pretty well today for only
having done this for three months.
今日のライブ
ギター始めて３か月かそこらで
よく頑張った
あっ あああ…
え？　郁代って誰だっけ？
Huh? Who's Ikuyo again?
ヘッ ヘヘヘ… 誰でしょうね
Dunno! Who'd have a crummy
old name like that?!
そんな しわしわネーム
だ… 誰のことかな？
It's your name, isn't it?!
お前の名前だろ！
Oh, it's Kita-chan's name?
ああ 喜多ちゃんか～
That face is contagious, huh?
その顔 伝染するんですか
あ～あ ずっと隠してたのに！
I hid it for so long!
I hate my name so much!
この名前 嫌なんですよ！
なんで？　かわいいじゃん
How come? It's cute.
うん
You wouldn't understand,
since you have a beautiful name
店長さんみたいに
“星の歌”なんて書く
すてきネームの人には
分かりませんよ！
that means "song of the stars"!
Look at her freak out!
おっ 荒れてるねえ
But mine sounds like a bad pun!
だって ダジャレみたいでしょ？
"Kita! Ikuyo!" (I'm here! Let's go!)
“きた～”“いくよ”って…
アハハ アホか～い
アハハッ アハハハハ…
Are you serious?!
おい ぶっ壊れたぞ
I think we broke her.
私のフルネームは 喜多喜多です
My full name is Kita Kita.
プッ なんか弱ってるの
新鮮で面白い
Seeing you withdraw into your shell is fun.
You're sadistic.
お前 性格悪いな
So, as for what you were saying before...
で… さっきの話だけど
え？
You were mumbling about supporting yourself
with the guitar and becoming a NEET.
ほら
ギターで食えないとニートとか
ブツブツ言ってたじゃん
I-I'm sorry for losing my head...
あっ あっ…
取り乱して すみません
あっ いや 謝ることないけど
Hey, nothin' wrong with it.
But lemme give you some advice
as your senpai in the world of bands.
先輩バンドマンとして
ひと言 言わせてもらうけどさ
Just chill out and enjoy yourself!
まっ 気楽に楽しく活動しなよ
えっ？
If you put the weight of success
on your own shoulders all the time,
漠然と
成功することばかり考えてると
つらくなっちゃいますもんね
you'll just make yourself miserable.
That's right.
そうそう
It's important to enjoy the process
of making your dream come true.
夢をかなえてくプロセスを
楽しんでくのが大事だからな
By the way, Senpai, how come
you suddenly quit playing?
っていうか 先輩は どうして
バンド 急に
辞めちゃったんですか？
えっ て… 店長さん
バンドしてたんですか？
Th-The manager was in a band?
Oh, yah. They were super popular.
そうだよ～
すごい人気だったんだから
じゃ… じゃあ なんで…
Then wh-why...
I got sick of bands.
飽きたんだよ バンド
But you run a club.
What's the deal there, huh?
え～？
ならライブハウスの店長してるの
矛盾してるじゃん
Shut up and drink.
Nijika-chan never said a word about that...
そんな話 虹夏ちゃん ひと言も…
What, I can? Thanks a bunch!
Huh? And Nijika-chan's been gone a while...
あれ？　そういえば虹夏ちゃん
なかなか戻ってこないな
I'm not paying for you, though.
Aww...
E-Excuse me.
あっ すみません
ちょっとトイレ…
I have to use the restroom.
Manager, keep 'em comin'!
店員さん 同じの下さ～い！
E-Excuse me... Nijika-chan?
あの 虹夏ちゃん？
ん？
ああ ぼっちちゃん
Oh, Bocchi-chan!
I-Is something the matter?
ど… どうかしたんですか？
ああ いや ちょっと涼んでただけ
Nah, just getting some fresh air.
I-It's been getting cold
at night lately, huh?
さ… 最近は もう夜は涼しいですね
そうだね～
あ～ 気付いたら
Sure has.
Next thing we know,
summer break's gonna be over!
もうすぐ夏休みも終わりか～
何も聞こえない
何も知らない…
I hear nothing.
I know nothing.
ん？
Summer break never ends.
夏休みは終わらない
私は学生なんかじゃない…
I'm not a student.
Trees, water, planets, Milky Way...
Bocchi-chan! Back to reality!
ぼっちちゃん 現実を見て！
ハッ　す… すみません
S-Sorry.
E-Excuse me...
あっ あの…
あのさ
Say...
I realized something while I was
watching you play today.
今日の演奏見て
気付いたんだけど
ぼっちちゃんが
ギターヒーローなんでしょ？
You're guitarhero, aren't you?
えっ！
W-Well, a-actually, n-no, about that...
うっ いやいや あの ちがちが…
あの その…
It was pretty obvious from the
on-point way you were strumming.
あのキレのあるストロークを
聴いたら分かったよ
And I finally noticed
you had the same guitar.
今更だけど
そういえば ギターも一緒だし
あっ うう…
ごまかすのは無理か…
No use trying to hide it now.
Um...
あっ えっと…
I am.
そうです
B-But I didn't hide it on purpose.
で… でも
わざと隠してたんじゃなくて
S-Since I'm anything but a hero right now...
い… 今の私なんて
まだ全然 ヒーロー
なんかじゃないし
I w-wanted to wait to tell you
until I fixed the way I am.
この性格を直してから
話したかったんです
E-Especially you, Nijika-chan.
と… 特に
虹夏ちゃんには
フッ
わ… 私と知ってショックですか？
A-Are you shocked to find out?
Nah...
ううん　むしろ
ぼっちちゃんで よかったと思った
It made me all the more happy to have you!
What?
えっ？
See, I told you I had a dream before, right?
あのさ
あたし 本当の夢があるって
前に言ったよね？
あっ はい
Y-Yes?
My mom died when I was little,
and my dad was never home,
あたし 小さいころに
母親が亡くなって
父親は いつも家にいないし
お姉ちゃんだけが家族だったんだ
so my sister was pretty much my only family.
お姉ちゃんがバンド始めてからは
But since I hated being alone,
when my sis started a band,
寂しがる あたしを
ライブハウスに
連れてってくれるようになったの
I had her take me to her clubs all the time.
It all seemed so shining to me.
あのころの あたしには
全部がキラキラして見えて
I was never happier anywhere else.
すごく幸せな空間で
そんな あたしを見てたから
I was her inspiration for quitting her band
and starting up this club.
お姉ちゃんはバンドを辞めて
ライブハウスを始めて…
STARRYはね
Starry is a place my sister made for me.
お姉ちゃんが あたしのために
作ってくれた場所なんだよ
お姉ちゃんは 絶対
そんなこと言わないけどね
Though I'll bet she won't admit it.
So my real dream
だから あたしの本当の夢はね
is to make a band popular
enough for me and my sister
お姉ちゃんの分まで
人気のあるバンドになること！
and make Starry even more famous!
スターリーを
もっと有名にすること！
あ…
But when I actually started my band,
でも バンド始めてみたら
あたしの夢って無謀なんじゃないか
って思うときもあって
I spent a while thinking that
it was kind of out of my reach.
And everyone was so disheartened today.
今日だって みんな
自信なくしちゃったし
But every time things
are looking their worst,
でも とんでもなくヤバい状況を
いつも壊してくれたのが…
Ripe Mangos
ぼっちちゃんだったよね
you're the one who breaks through it for us!
あっ
今日のぼっちちゃん あたしには
本当にヒーローに見えたよ
Bocchi-chan, you were
one heck of a hero to me today.
Ryo wants to use this band to finally
get to play music from the heart,
リョウは今度こそ このバンドで
自分たちの音楽をやること
and Kita-chan wants to really
do something with us.
喜多ちゃんは みんなで
何かをすることに憧れてる
They've all invested their hopes in the band.
みんな大事な思いを
バンドに託してるんだ
That reminds me, you never actually told me
what you were doing the band for now.
そういえば ぼっちちゃんが
今 なんのためにバンドしてるか
結局 聞いてなかったよね
I...
あっ 私は…
As a guitarist, I want to make the
Kessoku Band we all care so much about
ギタリストとして
みんなの大切な結束バンドを
最高のバンドにしたいです！
the best band it can be!
あ…
A-And I want us to become such a popular band
あっ ああ… それで
全員で人気バンドになって
that we can make money
and not have to finish school...
う… 売れて 学校中退したい
アハハッ なんか重いなあ
That's a pretty tall order!
But I accept your investment!
でも 託された
エヘヘヘッ
I sure do wish you could play the way
you do in your videos every time, though...
ああ～ ぼっちちゃんの演奏が
動画のときみたいに
毎回 発揮できたら
いいんだけどな～
あっ が… 頑張ります
I'll d-do my best...
But now I know it for sure!
でも あたし 確信したんだ
Having you with us will
make our dreams possible!
ぼっちちゃんがいたら
夢をかなえられるって！
えっ…
だから
これからも たくさん見せてね
So keep showing us more and more.
ぼっちちゃんのロック
Of "Bocchi-chan's rock."
あ…
Bocchi the Rock!
“ぼっち･ざ･ろっく”を！
ウフッ
あっ…
Okay!
はい！
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#08 Bocchi the Rock
What's wrong with being young?
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#08 Bocchi the Rock
Hey, why doesn't it stop?
The rhythm that I can't stop
keeps reverberating through my body
The melody playing in my earphones
is the only thing that lets me be who I am
The sky is tinged in red
But what color is my soul?
Tell me
where should I go?
I've always been searching
for something precious (hey!)
If everything's going to be lost some day
let's engrave it as deep as we can (now!)
My most pathetic nights
and cackling laughter
And days when I couldn't say
more than "You know..."
(I'm alive now, yeah Springtime of life)
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
What's wrong with being young?
#09 Enoshima Escar
Watch it!
見てください